<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on Greenery&#39;s Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/categories/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on Greenery&#39;s Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 14:36:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Greenery-S.github.io/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Argo Workflow 6</title>
      <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 14:36:26 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-6/</guid>
      <description>Argo Workflow (6) 1 Conditionals Supports conditional execution. The syntax is implemented by govaluate, which provides support for complex syntax. See the following example:&#xA;apiVersion: argoproj.io/v1alpha1 kind: Workflow metadata: generateName: coinflip- spec: entrypoint: coinflip templates: - name: coinflip steps: # flip a coin - - name: flip-coin template: flip-coin # evaluate the result in parallel - - name: heads template: heads # call heads template if &amp;#34;heads&amp;#34; when: &amp;#34;{{steps.flip-coin.outputs.result}} == heads&amp;#34; - name: tails template: tails # call tails template if &amp;#34;tails&amp;#34; when: &amp;#34;{{steps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argo Workflow 5</title>
      <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:58:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-5/</guid>
      <description>Argo Workflow (5) 1 Loops When writing workflows, it is often useful to iterate over a set of inputs. This is how Argo Workflows handle looping.&#xA;There are three basic ways to run a template multiple times:&#xA;withSequence iterates over a sequence of numbers. withItems accepts a list of items to process, which can be: Plain single values, accessible via {{item}} in the template. JSON objects, where each element can be referenced by its key as {{item.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argo Workflow 4</title>
      <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 22:25:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-4/</guid>
      <description>Argo Workflow (4) 1 Secrets Argo Workflow supports the use of Kubernetes Secrets within workflows. A Secret is an object used to store sensitive information, such as passwords, OAuth tokens, etc. Secrets can be stored in Etcd in plain text or base64 encoded form. When using a Secret in a workflow, you need to define a secrets field in the workflow spec, and then reference it in the workflow template using {{workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argo Workflow 3</title>
      <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 17:14:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-3/</guid>
      <description>Argo Workflow (3) 1 Artifacts When running workflows, it is very common for steps to generate or use artifacts. Typically, an output artifact from one step may be used as an input artifact by a subsequent step.&#xA;The following workflow specification contains two sequential steps. The first step, named generate-artifact, uses the argosay template to generate an artifact, which is then used by the second step, named print-message, which consumes the generated artifact.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argo Workflow 2</title>
      <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 14:30:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-2/</guid>
      <description>Argo Workflow (2) 1 Steps Multi-step workflows can be defined through the steps field. Each step is an independent container that can be executed in parallel.&#xA;apiVersion: argoproj.io/v1alpha1 kind: Workflow metadata: generateName: steps- spec: entrypoint: hello-hello-hello # This spec contains two templates: hello-hello-hello and whalesay templates: - name: hello-hello-hello # Instead of just running a container # This template has a sequence of steps steps: - - name: hello1 # hello1 is run before the following steps template: argosay arguments: parameters: - name: message value: &amp;#34;hello1&amp;#34; - - name: hello2a # double dash =&amp;gt; run after previous step template: argosay arguments: parameters: - name: message value: &amp;#34;hello2a&amp;#34; - name: hello2b # single dash =&amp;gt; run in parallel with previous step template: argosay arguments: parameters: - name: message value: &amp;#34;hello2b&amp;#34; # This is the same template as from the previous example - name: argosay inputs: parameters: - name: message container: image: yky8/argosay:v2 command: [ &amp;#34;/usr/local/bin/argosay&amp;#34; ] args: [ &amp;#34;echo&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;{{inputs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argo Workflow 1</title>
      <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 03:46:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/argo-workflow-1/</guid>
      <description>Argo Workflow (1) A lot of examples can be found here: https://github.com/argoproj/argo-workflows/tree/main/examples However, since the docker/whalesay image is no longer supported, many examples cannot run, and you need to build an image to replace it.&#xA;1 Argo CLI argo submit hello-world.yaml # submit a workflow spec to Kubernetes argo list # list current workflows argo get hello-world-xxx # get info about a specific workflow argo logs hello-world-xxx # print the logs from a workflow argo delete hello-world-xxx # delete workflow You can also use kubectl, but you need to specify the namespace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start With Self Build Image</title>
      <link>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/quick-start-with-self-build-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 02:17:44 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Greenery-S.github.io/posts/devops/argo-workflow/quick-start-with-self-build-image/</guid>
      <description>A Somewhat Rocky &amp;ldquo;Quick&amp;rdquo; Start Recently, I wanted to review Argo Workflow, so I decided to start from the official documentation and follow the steps one by one. However, things didn&amp;rsquo;t go as smoothly as expected. The official docker/whalesay image is no longer supported in the latest Docker version, which has caused hundreds of hello world examples based on it to fail to run properly. So, I decided to build my own image to replace the official docker/whalesay image.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
